

///====== questions array===========//
var questions = [
    {
        id:"1",
        question: "What is the full form of RAM",
        answer: "Random Access Memory",
        options:[
            "Random Access Memory",
            "Randomy Access Memory",
            "Run All Memory",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"2",
        question: "MS-Word is an example of _____",
        answer:  "Application software",
        options:[
            "An operating system",
            "A processing device",
            "Application software",
            "An input device"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"3",
        question: "A computer cannot boot if it does not have the _____",
        answer: "Operating system",
        options:[
            "Compiler",
            "Loader",
            "Assembler",
            "Operating system"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"4",
        question: "Ctrl, Shift and Alt are called .......... keys.",
        answer: "modifier",
        options:[
            "modifier",
            "function",
            "adjustment",
            "alphanumeric"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"5",
        question: "The first computer was programmed using .......",
        answer: "Machine language",
        options:[
            "Assembly language",
            "Machine language",
            "Spaghetti code",
            "Source code"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"6",
        question: " _______ is a software program used to view Web pages.",
        answer: "browser",
        options:[
            "site",
            "host",
            "browser",
            "link"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"7",
        question: ".......is approximately one billion bytes",
        answer: "Gigabyte",
        options:[
            "Megabyte",
            "Gigabyte",
            "Terabyte",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"8",
        question: "C, BASIC, COBOL, and Java are examples of....language",
        answer: "high-level",
        options:[
            "low-level",
            "programming",
            "computer",
            "high-level"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"9",
        question: "What is a default file extension for all word documents?",
        answer: "DOC",
        options:[
            "TXT",
            "WRD",
            "FIL",
            "DOC"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"10",
        question: "The instructions for starting the computer are housed in",
        answer: "ROM Chip",
        options:[
            "RAM",
            "CD-ROM",
            "ROM Chip",
            "None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"11",
        question: "The first mechanical computer designed by Charles Babbage ?",
        answer: "Analytical Engine",
        options:[
            "Abacus",
            "Processor",
            "Analytical Engine",
            "Calculator"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"12",
        question: "Which is a single integrated circuit?",
        answer: "Gate",
        options:[
            "Gate",
            "Mother Board",
            "CPU",
            "Chip"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"13",
        question: "Web pages are written using ?",
        answer: "HTML",
        options:[
            "FTP",
            "HTTP",
            "URL",
            "HTML"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"14",
        question: "India’s first super computer is ?",
        answer: "Param",
        options:[
            "Agni",
            "Flow solver",
            "Trisul",
            "Param"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"15",
        question: "Which of the following is NOT operating system ?",
        answer: "Java",
        options:[
            "Dos",
            "Unix",
            "Window NT",
            "Java"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"16",
        question: "One byte is equivalent to ?",
        answer: "8 bits",
        options:[
            "4 bits",
            "8 bits",
            "32 bits",
            "12 bits"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"17",
        question: "What is the full form of lP ?",
        answer: "Internet protocol",
        options:[
            "Interface program",
            "Interface protocol",
            "Internet protocol",
            "Internet program"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"18",
        question: "A terabyte comprises ?",
        answer: "1024 gigabyte",
        options:[
            "1024 kilobyte",
            "1024 gigabyte",
            "1024 megabyte",
            "1024 byte"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"19",
        question: "The most widely used computer device is",
        answer: "Internal hard disk",
        options:[
            "Solid state disks",
            "Solid state disks",
            "Internal hard disk",
            "Mouse"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"20",
        question: "How many recent files you can display on File menu at maximum?",
        answer: "9",
        options:[
            "3",
            "7",
            "9",
            "12"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"21",
        question: "Information on a computer is stored as",
        answer: "digital data",
        options:[
            "digital data",
            "hybrid data",
            "analog data",
            "modem data"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"22",
        question: "Which one is the first search engine in internet",
        answer: "Archie",
        options:[
            "Google",
            "Archie",
            "WAIS",
            "Altavista"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"23",
        question: "Which is responsible for communication between Memory and ALU?",
        answer: "Control Unit",
        options:[
            "Keyboard",
            "RAM",
            "USB",
            "Control Unit"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"24",
        question: "Speed of second generation computers was in ------ second.",
        answer: "micro",
        options:[
            "micro",
            "nano",
            "milli",
            "pico"
        ]
    },
    {
        id:"25",
        question: "Which of the following is the most powerful type of computer ?",
        answer: "Super computer",
        options:[
            "Super–micro",
            "Super conductor",
            "Megaframe",
            "Super computer"
        ]
    },
];








